When patriots become heroes.
Captain America: The First Avenger is a action, adventure,
science fiction film directed by Joe Johnston.
During World War II, Steve Rogers is a sickly man from Brooklyn who's
transformed into super-soldier Captain America to aid in the war effort.
Rogers must stop the Red Skull – Adolf Hitler's ruthless head of weaponry, and the leader of an
organization that intends to use a mysterious device of untold powers for world domination.
Captain America / Steve Rogers, played by Chris Evans.
Peggy Carter, played by Hayley Atwell.
James Buchanan 'Bucky' Barnes, played by Sebastian Stan.
Colonel Chester Phillips, played by Tommy Lee Jones.
Johann Schmidt / Red Skull, played by Hugo Weaving.
Howard Stark, played by Dominic Cooper.
Captain America: The First Avenger is a 2011 American superhero film
based on the Marvel Comics character Captain America.
Produced by Marvel Studios and distributed by Paramount Pictures, it is
the fifth film in the Marvel Cinematic Universe (MCU).
The film was directed by Joe Johnston, written by Christopher Markus and Stephen McFeely, and stars Chris Evans as Steve Rogers / Captain America alongside
Tommy Lee Jones, Hugo Weaving, Hayley Atwell, Sebastian Stan, Dominic Cooper, Toby Jones, Neal McDonough, Derek Luke, and Stanley Tucci.
During World War II, Rogers, a frail man, is transformed into the super-soldier Captain America and must stop
the Red Skull (Weaving) from using the Tesseract as an energy source for world domination.
The film began as a concept in 1997 and was scheduled for
distribution by Artisan Entertainment.
However, a lawsuit disrupted the project and was
not settled until September 2003.
In 2005, Marvel Studios received a loan from Merrill Lynch, and planned to
finance and release the film through Paramount Pictures.
Directors Jon Favreau and Louis Leterrier were interested in directing
the project before Johnston was approached in 2008.
The principal characters were cast between March and June 2010.
Production began in June, and filming took place in London,
Manchester, Caerwent, Liverpool, and Los Angeles.
Several different techniques were used by the visual effects company Lola to create the
physical appearance of the character before he becomes Captain America.
Captain America: The First Avenger premiered at the El Capitan Theatre in Los Angeles on July 19,
2011, and was released in the United States on July 22, as part of Phase One of the MCU.
The film was commercially successful, grossing over $370 million worldwide, and received positive reviews from critics,
who praised Evans' performance, the film's depiction of its 1940s time period, and Johnston's direction.
Two direct sequels have been released: Captain America: The Winter
Soldier (2014) and Captain America: Civil War (2016).
The film explores themes of new york city, nazi,
superhero, world war ii, heroism.
The tone is thought_provoking.